

René Louis Warren

warrenlr@gmail.com 778 . 386 . 4192 http://renewarren.ca

Scientist with 20+ yrs experience in biotechnology, genomics, informatics. I:

Developed the first *de novo* genome assembly software with emerging short DNA sequences

Discovered *Fusobacterium* in colon cancer, one of *Time Magazine*'s 2011 top ten breakthrough

Coordinated bioinformatics analyses of Rhodococus, Cryptococcus, Bullfrog, Spruce genomes

I am seeking new challenges & additional leadership

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2017 - now

Group Leader

BC Cancer Agency - Genome Sciences Centre, Vancouver

- Lead group, provide project management, expertise & guidance
- Conceptualize / lead development of genome analysis technologies
- Interview, supervise, mentor COOP students and staff

2002 - 17

Coordinator

BC Cancer Agency - Genome Sciences Centre, Vancouver

- Lead bioinformatics software R&D (Python, PERL, R, unix)
- Published research (scientific journals, international conferences)
- Interviewed, taught, trained, supervised biologists and programmers

2000 - 01

Officer

NRC - CNRC - Biotechnology Research Institute, Montréal

- Engineered gene expression regulation technology (molec/cell biology)
- Designed, fabricated, tested components of DNA "gene switch"
- Collaborated with stakeholders, chemists, molecular and cell biologists

EDUCATION

2000 – 01	Certificate Computer Science	Concordia University
1997 – 99	MSc Biochemistry & Molecular Biology	UBC
1994 – 97	BSc Biochemistry Dean's Honours List	Université de Montréal
2015, 16 2011 2009 2007 1998 1997 1996 1995	ADDITIONAL INFORMATION Awarded the John Jambor Knowledge Fund for presenting at conferences Interviewed by NTN24 channel for Fusobacterium discovery colon cancer Interviewed by Genome Technology to discuss next-generation sequencing Interviewed by GenomeWeb for the development of SSAKE Awarded the UBC Graduate Fellowship for MSc studies Awarded Fonds de la Recherche en Santé Québec (FRSQ) for BSc studies Awarded Bursary from FRSQ for BSc honour's research project Worked at NASA to coordinate the crystallization of proteins under microgravity: CMIX-4 payload, space shuttle Endeavour	
PRESENTATIONS (Selected from 16)		
2017, 18 2015, 16 2008, 12, 15 2010	Research in Computational Molecular Biology, Intelligent Systems for Molecular Biology, Dubli Pacific Symposium on Biocomputing, Kona, Ha Sequencing, Finishing and Analysis in the Futur	n UK / Orlando USA talks waii USA posters

PUBLICATIONS

Synthetic Biology 3.0 conference, Zürich, Switzerland

(Selected from 58 peer-reviewed *co-first authors)

Warren RL. 2018. Visualizing genome synteny with xmatchview. J. Open Source Software. 3:497

Warren RL, et al. 2015. LINKS: Scalable, alignment-free scaffolding of draft genomes with long reads. *GigaScience* 4:35

Warren RL, et al. 2012. Derivation of HLA types from shotgun sequence datasets. Genome Med. 4:95

Castellarin M*, **Warren RL***, *et al.* 2012. Fusobacterium nucleatum infection is prevalent in human colorectal carcinoma. *Genome Research*. 22:299-306

Warren RL, et al. 2007. Assembling millions of short DNA sequences using SSAKE. Bioinfo. 23:500

REFERENCES

Available upon request

talk

2007